## Preet Khasakia . Jarvis Consulting

I am a recent graduate out of Ontario Tech University in Bachelors of Engineering, Software. Throughout my years in undergrad I worked on various projects, both team-oritented and individual, in several engineering courses where I gained knowledge in different programming languages such as Java, C, Web programming and Python with the addition of excelling in research, problem solving and contributing with team members. Coursework in distributed systems, cloud computing and Capstone I/II had a great deal of hands-on experience with the ability to grow in a team-oriented work environment. I have joined Jarvis Consulting Group as a Software Engineer trainee that enables me to improve my skillset, as well as familiarize with real-world projects, and continue to progress throughout the program.

#### Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: Python, C/C++, PSQL, HTML, CSS Familiar: Docker, Bash, Arduino, AWS, Heroku

### **Jarvis Projects**

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_PreetKhasakia/

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Designed and implemented a linux cluster agent to preserve and monitor real-time data of nodes running on CentOS. Application performs real-time data collection of hardware specifications and CPU memory usage. Created a Data Definition Language (DDL) script to hold specified data into tables used in the database. Modified 'host\_info.sh' and 'host\_usage.sh' to retrieve the necessary and insert it to the database.

#### Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Grep App: Created a java application that mimics the Linux 'grep' command to search and retrieve matching strings from a given file. Technologies used for this project are Maven, Java, Docker and IntelliJ IDE. Implementation of the backend uses Encapsulation and an interface to provide a flexible, organised implementation of the program. Deployment is done by dockerizing the app which includes building an image locally, running the docker container and pushing the it to Docker Hub to verify the image.
- JDBC App: The JDBC API establishes a connection between the java Customer program to a PostgreSQL database instance. The basic flow of the JDBC app follows a simple process of mounting the driver, followed by creating a connection to the database, executing SQL statements, commit/rollback and finally closing the connection. The application consists of multiple java classes, each with its own function that allows the user to access database elements with pre-defined SQL queries within the Customer DAO class.

#### **Highlighted Projects**

IOT Smart Home Security System: Built and established all hardware components to achieve a fully functioning security system. Contributed to developing a security system application, allowing users to control the system remotely. Integrated Amazon Alexa that features a voice command capability to remotely arm/disarm the system.

**PizzaRia Cloud Application**: Implemented custom location markers of an embedded Google Maps to show different store locations of PizzaRia. Incorporated a class to handle user inputs of updated selections made by a user, stored via RDS database on AWS. Implemented an emailing service for users to show the receipt of their order with location and order summary.

#### Professional Experiences

Software Engineer, Jarvis (Oct 2021-present): Working in an agile workflow environment along side other engineers to manage and complete various software projects. Appointed as a team lead for a sprint session and conducted daily scrum meetings with my team of data engineers to stay updated and acknowledge everyones daily tasks. Completed project work through tickets and followed the Gitflow approach to allow senior developers to review the work on Github.

Software Packaging Assistant, Ontario Tech University (April 2021 - August 2021): Revised existing software installation documents and acquired the latest versions of software and licensing compatible for the upcoming school year. Executed compatibility testing of vendor-supplied installations to validate applications on various Operating Systems.

Resolved scripting errors, automation defects and compatibility issues to certify packaged software. Used SCCM to deploy applications for faculty and institution personnel.

# Education

Ontario Tech University (September 2017 - April 2021), Bachelor of Engineering, Software, Electrical and Computer Engineering

### Miscellaneous

- Rookie barber
- Gym
- $\bullet$  Basketball